Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Garma's Fate
Will your father, Sovereign Degwin,
be visiting Earth in the near future?
I haven't heard of any such plans.
If he visits, it would be
a pleasure to serve him.
Excuse me. I'll see you later.
Oh, Garma always looks so gallant!
How elegant!
I'm going to faint!
I can't stand these fools.
They'd all be in a panic if they knew
about the Trojan Horse and its mobile suits.
That's right. We can't build
an anti-Trojan Horse task force...
...since the front lines
are stretched too thin.
Garma. Who's that gentleman over there?
Well, there are a number of ways
of dealing with it...
The former mayor, Eschoenbach.
He hates Zeon, but...
...he's stayed here to watch over
the civilian population.
Sounds like a stubborn old man.
Presenting Icelina Eschoenbach!
- Oh my.
- How lovely!
- Really, now...
- Quite the beauty!
If you'll excuse me.
Romance on the front lines, huh?
It's just like Garma, the spoiled rich kid.
He says he cannot let his daughter
marry a son of the Zabi family...
...which reigns over the Zeon forces?
Yes.
That certainly sounds like your father.
I don't care about Zeon
or the Federation.
You're my Garma.
I love you.
Icelina.
I want to be with you, even if
it means betraying my father.
I can't afford to betray
my father and Zeon, but...
Don't worry. I have a chance to capture
some important Federation secrets.
If that goes well...
...even my father will surely grant me
my impossible wish.
Oh, Garma.
And if he still denies me...
...then I am prepared
to abandon Zeon.
Garma...
Captain Garma!
What is it?
Oh, excuse me...
Never mind that. Speak!
Yes.
The Trojan Horse has reached the S-3 point.
What?!
If they pass this last defensive line...
...they'll escape into Federation airspace.
Just as I planned.
There's another defensive line there.
I will be headed there myself
with a mobile squadron.
Inform Lt. Commander Char.
Mobilize!
Yes, sir!
But Garma...
Once I capture the Federation's
new weapons...
...I'll bring them to the homeland.
And you will be by my side.
The Zeon forces won't let us out of this city.
Yes. But if things continue like this...
Mr. Bright.
I can take a forward position
and act as a decoy.
No. That won't work. It's too late.
What?
Something's shown up on our sound detector.
Enemy formation
approaching from the north.
Are there any Gaw's?
There's one.
And it's accompanied by fighters.
Then that's all the more reason!
I can lure them away!
And the White Base can escape to the sea
in the meantime.
No. Luring them away
and breaking through...
A flare!
There, in front of us...
That's a domed baseball stadium.
Um... Yes, I see it.
Right. Hide the White Base in there.
It should fit.
Why?
To avoid being detected by the enemy...
...the White Base will cease all operations.
We'll watch their movements, and then...
Mr. Bright!
I disagree! If we do that...
Amuro, in the Gundam.
Kai, in the Guncannon.
Ryu and Hayato, standby in the Guntank.
Don't forget that
we still have civilians on board.
I'm a civilian too.
All crew standby at level 1 battle stations.
Don't make a sound
until I give further orders.
Please stay in your rooms, everyone!
Turn about, 180 degrees!
Yes, sir! Turning 180 degrees!
I feel like I'm suffocating.
What are they doing? If we're going to die,
we might as well leave the ship now.
If we escape into the city, we can survive...!
Everyone.
We've made it this far. Please stay calm.
If we put our hearts together
and fight as one, we will be saved!
But...
Oh dear...
Hey, don't shine that light on him. Honestly!
There there...
What are you doing?
Here. Give him to me for a moment.
See, you don't have to cry anymore. Right?
My baby! My baby!
I'm so sorry! I looked away for one second
and we got separated!
Oh, I'm glad you're all right.
Patrol Lugguns! What do you mean,
you can't find the Trojan Horse?!
They haven't left the city!
Search harder!
The only way to flush out a rat in a hole...
...is with a bit of carpet bombing.
Right.
Very well. All units! Deploy roller shifts
and commence bombing immediately!
Yes, sir!
It's all right. It's all right.
It would be a miracle if we didn't get hit.
Please! Someone! Come quickly!
The young mistress is...
Let go of me!
There's no way that you could understand!
Mistress. Going now would be
like going to your death.
Mistress, you must not...!
Your father is calling.
How dare you! You ill-mannered brutes!
Mistress! Come on, now!
No...!
There's somewhere I need to be!
Now let go of me! Let go!
I have nothing to say to my father!
So, I hear the son of Zeon's leader...
...wants to marry you?
Father, you can't deny me my freedom!
I have the right to choose my own path.
I won't allow it!
Listen well...
Don't let Icelina have the keys to the jet.
Yes, sir!
Oh, Garma...
Mobile Suit
Well? Has the Trojan Horse come out?
No, sir. Not yet.
Where is it? Why won't it come out?
They're starting to understand
the art of war.
We're going to have to go down and find it.
Now, wait.
If that's what you want to do,
I'll go down with my men.
Would you really do that for me?
Of course I would. You are my superior.
For now, perhaps... but you served
directly under my older brother, Dozle.
I must...
You seem unusually agitated.
Don't be hasty for glory just because of a girl.
Try to calm down.
I'll leave it to you.
Good.
So he thinks I'm anxious
because of Icelina?
Silly...
I am calm.
Char.
Inform me as soon as you see
the Trojan Horse or the mobile suits.
I'll destroy them with the Gaw.
I'm honored that you came to see me off.
I'll do as you request.
Good luck, Garma.
I'm counting on you, Char.
May the glory of victory be yours.
Bright, three Zakus are coming down.
They're headed directly this way.
Right. Amuro, do you read?
Zakus are approaching. Move the Gundam
away from the White Base.
Roger!
And we'll go with your battle plan.
You'll lure the Zakus...
...and, if possible, the main enemy forces...
...into the area in front of the White Base.
Amuro...
Then we'll strike with
the White Base's weapons.
Roger.
Guntank and Guncannon,
stand by In front of the White Base as well.
Here I go!
Over there.
It seems that misleading soldiers
on my own side...
...doesn't sit too well with me.
Let's see. That mobile suit should be
out of the Trojan Horse by now.
He saw me!
That's strange.
No, he's there! The enemy is near!
Damn!
It's Char!
I can't let him hit me.
That damned mobile suit is getting better.
Good try, mobile suit.
Are you trying to lure us out?
Which would mean...
the Trojan Horse is behind you.
I see. That's a pretty good plan.
Let me use it for my own revenge.
I've been waiting, Char.
The mobile suit is escaping!
The Trojan Horse is ahead!
Can you pursue?
I will.
Ready beam cannons!
All units, standby for attack!
Bright. The enemy fighters are moving away.
All right, Mirai. Get back in position.
We're going to attack!
Yes, sir!
Guntank! Guncannon!
All White Base gunners!
Coordinate your targeting.
Fire barrage in 10 seconds!
10... 9...
8... 7... 6...
5... 4... 3...
2... 1...
Fire!
What's going on?!
Enemy fire from behind!
From behind?!
It's the Trojan Horse!
Attacking from behind!
Climb! Climb right now!
Not possible, sir!
Turn about, 180 degrees!
I'll ram the Gaw into the Trojan Horse!
Garma, if you can still hear me,
blame this on the misfortune of your birth.
What?! Misfortune?!
That's right! Misfortune!
Char, you...!
You were a good friend to me, but...
Your father is the one to blame.
Char! You planned this!
Char!
I am a man of the Zabi family!
My death will not be in vain!
One enemy aircraft heading for us!
What?!
It can't be...! They're going to ram us!
Mirai! Climb! Climb now!
Emergency ascent!
Everyone take cover!
Glory to the Principality of Zeon!
We made it...
Amuro, you did well.
Our breakthrough plan worked.
We will escape now. Return to ship.
Amuro, what's wrong?! Amuro!
I understand! Returning to ship!
I see. I understand.
Thank you. I will inform my daughter.
Icelina...
Father...
Icelina, Garma has apparently died in battle.
What?!
Garma!
Why?! Why did this happen?!
The nation of space colonies which calls itself
the Principality of Zeon...
...floats on the far side of the moon.
News of the death of Garma, the Zabi family's
youngest son, has just arrived.
Degwin Zabi, the Sovereign of
the Principality of Zeon...
...and the father of Garma...
...couldn't help dropping his cane
before the messenger.
There is no end to battle.
Garma's remaining forces
launch a vengeful assault.
With Ryu in the Guncannon...
...Amuro tries to destroy the Gaw, but...
...a beautiful girl stands in the way.
Her trembling hands clutch a gun
aimed at Amuro.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Icelina - Love's Remains.
Next Time
Icelina - Love's Remains
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...